Guide to the Geoffrey Chester papers, 1964-2014.
Geoffrey Chester papers,
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Geoffrey Chester papers, 1964-2014.
14-22-4202
Geoffrey Chester
3 cubic feet.
{**Comma Separated List Of Material Formats,End With Period**.}
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Includes correspondence and subject files pertaining to Chester's career at Cornell.
BIOGRAPHICAL NOTE
Chester was professor emeritus of physics and dean emeritus of Cornell's College of Arts and Sciences. He was an authority on liquid helium.
He received a B.S. from Edinburgh University in 1950 and a Ph.D. from King's College of London University in 1953.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
Includes correspondence and subject files pertaining to Chester's career at Cornell.
SUBJECTS
Names:
Chester, Geoffrey; Cornell University. Department of Physics.; Cornell University -- Faculty.
Subjects:
Physics -- Study and teaching.; Physicists.; Universities and colleges -- Faculty
INFORMATION FOR USERS
CONTAINER LIST
- Manousakis and Reatto Pseudo-Dots Papers (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Papers- Surface Fluctuations, 1969-2000 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Irreversible Processes Papers (Englert), 1977-2000 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  Sticky Note: BASIC Surface Papers WLTE(Illegible) and Droplets; 14, 26, 41-55
- Coding Summaries and Homework, Undated (Box 1, Folder 4)
  Julius' Summary Data He 3/4
- Papers and Graphs- He Clusters, 1984 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  Badri- 2D
- Papers- Nucleation, 1974-1991 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  Nucleation Classical
- References and Notes- Drafting Failure, Undated (Box 1, Folder 7)
  Surface He- Sticky Note: Steve Stucky(Illegible)
- Papers- Neutron Scattering Exp., 1966-1999 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  Jim PROJECT
- Papers and Notes- Delta Potentials, 1997 (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Papers- He-He Potentials, 1978-1996 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  (DOBBS Corr) Recent Refheuen(Illegible) M.C. and all Hziz Potentials
- Papers- Reprints, Miscellaneous, 1966-1999 (Box 1, Folder 11)
- Papers- Reprints, Miscellaneous, 1979-1999 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  References
- Papers- Basic Variational/Exact Calculations, 1974-1997 (Box 1, Folder 13)
- Papers- Group, 1969-1991 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  Sticky Note: McK: Fax 011-44-131-226-5284
- Papers (and E-mail)- Older, 1969-2012 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  Sticky Note: Review
- Faculty of Applied Physics Information and Notes, 1993 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  A.E.P.
- Notes and Tables, Undated (Box 1, Folder 17)
- Paper from Prof. GV Chester and Cassette Tapes, 2000 (Box 1, Folder 18)
- Cornell Academic Calendar 2000-01, 2000-2001 (Box 1, Folder 20)
- Papers and Notes- Leipzig, 1977-1989 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  JIM: P^2exl vanives approx. (Illegible)
- Papers Regarding Monte Carlo Simulation and Thesis: Quantum Many Body Calculations, 1998-1999 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  Sticky Notes: 1. Mike-Thesis 2. Second Layer 3. 1st Layer-Graph
- Papers Regarding Shadow Wave Function, 1989-1999 (Box 1, Folder 23)
  Sticky Notes: 1. Shadows-Bulk 2. Shadows-Bulk 3. First Shadow 4. IMP. Binding
- Physical Review Editorial Material, Undated (Box 1, Folder 24)
  prbeups.org (Illegible)
- P.R.L. Rules, Undated (Box 1, Folder 25)
- Papers Regarding Vortexes, 1996-1999 (Box 1, Folder 26)
  Sticky Notes: 1. PRL. Vortex 2. Vortex-Cylinder 3. 2D Shadows 4. 2D Puddles
- Papers- Miscellaneous, 1987-1999 (Box 1, Folder 27)
  Sticky Notes: 1. 2D- Helium 2. First-Vacancy 3. BCC/HCP Vac.
- Papers- Miscellaneous, 1987-1992 (Box 1, Folder 28)
  Sticky Notes: 1. Finite T.H.S. 2. H-S El. Consts
- Papers- Monte Carlo Simulation and Van der Waals Study, 1976-1990 (Box 1, Folder 29)
  Sticky Note: H.D. Solid
- Papers- Miscellaneous, 1966-1980 (Box 1, Folder 30)
- Papers Regarding Monte Carlo Simulation, 1982-1988 (Box 1, Folder 31)
- Papers Regarding Monte Carlo Simulation, 1984-1991 (Box 1, Folder 32)
- Papers- Miscellaneous, 1981-1983 (Box 1, Folder 33)
- Papers- Miscellaneous, 1979-1981 (Box 1, Folder 34)
- Papers- Miscellaneous, 1976-1978 (Box 1, Folder 35)
- Papers- Miscellaneous, 1974-1976 (Box 1, Folder 36)
- Papers- Miscellaneous, 1966-1974 (Box 1, Folder 37)
- Unpublished Papers, 1974-07 (Box 1, Folder 38)
- Old Reprints- Miscellaneous, 1956-1971 (Box 2, Folder 1)
- Miscellaneous Materials: Pamphlet and Notes, 1940-1991 (Box 2, Folder 2)
- Curricula Vitae: Brown-Randel, Undated (Box 2, Folder 3)
- Information on DeKiewiet, Cornelis W., 1991 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  Photo included
- Information on O'Leary, Paul M., 1952-1957 (Box 2, Folder 5)
- Information on Cottrell, Leonard S. Jr., 1945-1949 (Box 2, Folder 6)
- Information on Mineka, Francis E., 1985 (Box 2, Folder 7)
- Information on Keast, W.R., 1957-1965 (Box 2, Folder 8)
- Information on Crane, Thomas F., 1896-1930 (Box 2, Folder 9)
- Information on Wilcox, Walter F., 1902-1907 (Box 2, Folder 10)
- Information on Hull, Henry C., 1913 (Box 2, Folder 11)
- Information on Hill, Albert R., 1907-1908 (Box 2, Folder 12)
- Information on Nichols, Edward L., 1867-1946 (Box 2, Folder 13)
- Information on Thilly, Frank, 1870-1934 (Box 2, Folder 14)
- Information on Ogden, Robert M., 1877-1959 (Box 2, Folder 15)
- Preliminary and Final reports of the President's Commission on Self-Governance, 1976-08-1976-12 (Box 2, Folder 16)
- Supplement to the Preliminary Report of the President's Commission on Self-Governance, 1976-09 (Box 2, Folder 17)
- Transparencies and Notes, Undated (Box 2, Folder 18)
  V.G. Xslaleratilv Juleus (Illegible)
- Transparencies: V.G. Vortices, Undated (Box 2, Folder 19)
- Transparencies, Undated (Box 2, Folder 20)
- Transparencies and Notes, Undated (Box 2, Folder 21)
- Blank Transparencies, Undated (Box 2, Folder 22)
- Transparencies: Film V.G., Undated (Box 2, Folder 23)
- Transparencies: Shadow-Wave-FNS. Talk, Undated (Box 2, Folder 24)
- Transparencies: V.G. Film, Undated (Box 2, Folder 25)
  Smooth Surfaces (Illegible)
- Papers: A. Griffin, Undated (Box 2, Folder 26)
- Papers: M.C. History, 1952-1957 (Box 2, Folder 27)
- Papers: D. Ceperley, 1978-1980 (Box 2, Folder 28)
  The Airy-Gas
- Recent References, Undated (Box 2, Folder 29)
- References: E/W, Undated (Box 2, Folder 30)
- Papers: A.A. Robb, Undated (Box 2, Folder 31)
- Papers: Nano-Tubes, 1995-1999 (Box 2, Folder 32)
- Papers: Nano-Tubes, 1998-1999 (Box 2, Folder 33)
- Miscellaneous Papers, 1994-1999 (Box 2, Folder 34)
- Older Papers: Ground-State He^4, 1964-1973 (Box 2, Folder 35)
- Miscellaneous Papers: Bill-Magra, 1988-1992 (Box 2, Folder 36)
- Miscellaneous Papers, 1996-1999 (Box 2, Folder 37)
- Recent Papers, 1999 (Box 2, Folder 38)
- David's PI Papers, 1976-1988 (Box 2, Folder 39)
- Miscellaneous Papers, 1968 (Box 2, Folder 40)
  G.N.C. ald Payen (Illegible)
- Correspondence, Notes, and Papers, 1999 (Box 2, Folder 41)
- Old Papers, 1954-1978 (Box 2, Folder 42)
  B.E.C.
- Space Surveys, Undated (Box 2, Folder 43)
- Film-Papers: Experimental (Chemistry), 1973-1993 (Box 2, Folder 44)
- Film-Papers: Classical (Chemistry), 1983-1990 (Box 2, Folder 45)
- Film-Papers: Quantum (Not Graphite), 1974-1996 (Box 2, Folder 46)
  Note: See Ranch 1-800-643-8899
- Film-Papers: Theory II, 1978-1994 (Box 2, Folder 47)
- Film-Papers: Theory II, 1970-1994 (Box 2, Folder 48)
- Vacancies-Solid-He^4 Theory Papers, 1968-1990 (Box 2, Folder 49)
- 2nd Layer ^4He Notes, 2000 (Box 2, Folder 50)
  Sticky Note: 10/2D He^4 and exoluver of diffusion and LRO: BEC; and spatial coder (Illegible)
- Draft 2nd Layer Papers, 1994-2000 (Box 2, Folder 51)
- Paula Paper, Final Copy, 1999-2000 (Box 2, Folder 52)
- Emails and Notes, 1998-1999 (Box 2, Folder 53)
  Mass 3 System on Ipaphile Calcium effective 3rd layer potentials
- Emails and Notes, 1998-1999 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  Badri-Paula Latest Pots
- Emails and Papers, 1997-1999 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  Paula New Film Work. Note: Send papers to Manausatics, xstil emerges Frey, Paula est (Illegible)
- Emails and Notes, 1997-1999 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  2nd Layer; Pepeli Figures, Tables-Data Sticky Note: Have 40 lines mene level Haye ^32 (Illegible)
- Papers, 1977-1991 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  ^3He- 2D and Film Condensation Papers
- References, Undated (Box 3, Folder 5)
  Paula Paper Refs
- Figures and Tables, Undated (Box 3, Folder 6)
  Mathematical equation on folder; Sticky note: Has same old loop (Illegible)
- Notes- Film, Undated (Box 3, Folder 7)
- Emails and Notes, 1999 (Box 3, Folder 8)
- Papers, 1995-1998 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  Refs. Granada
- Emails and Papers, 1996-1998 (Box 3, Folder 10)
- Graphs, 1996-10 (Box 3, Folder 11)
  Film Latest Version Oct 1996
- Emails and Papers (Surface-Pots) (Box 3, Folder 12)
  Films- Surface Potentials (See also AJIT. File) 2nd note: SenfvecSceence (Illegible) QD506 A1 597
- Papers (Mike-PRL-Vortex), 1995-1997 (Box 3, Folder 13)
  PRL Draft and Proofs
- Papers (Prague), 1997 (Box 3, Folder 14)
  Prague- Vortex
- Papers and Notes, 1994-1997 (Box 3, Folder 15)
- Emails and Papers, 1986-1999 (Box 3, Folder 16)
  Mike PRL Revisions
- Papers (^3He- Vortex), 1974-1976 (Box 3, Folder 17)
  Vortex- ^3He Trapping Papers
- Emails (from Krishnamachari Badrinarayan), 1997-1998 (Box 3, Folder 18)
- Notes and Graphs, Undated (Box 3, Folder 19)
  Film- Potentials Wave Forms and pes. (Illegible)
- Papers and Notes, 1966-1967 (Box 3, Folder 20)
  Vortex: Refs to Lattices
- Papers on Vortex Theory, 1958-2000 (Box 3, Folder 21)
- Papers on Vortex Theory, 1966-1970 (Box 3, Folder 22)
- Papers on Vortex Lattices, 1968 (Box 3, Folder 23)
- Papers on Spherical Vortex, 1894 (Box 3, Folder 24)
- Papers on Vortex Lines, 1960-1971 (Box 3, Folder 25)
- Papers, 1984 (Box 3, Folder 26)
  2D Papers Classical
- Papers, 1987-1994 (Box 3, Folder 27)
  2D Melting elt.
- Papers, 1969-1984 (Box 3, Folder 28)
- Papers and Notes, 1983-1997 (Box 3, Folder 29)
  New Hard Disc and 2D-Melting
- Papers (JZ- recent), 1981-1988 (Box 3, Folder 30)
- Papers and Notes, 1981-1993 (Box 3, Folder 31)
  3D- Drops. /Papers
- Papers, 1985-1991 (Box 3, Folder 32)
  Classical- Interface
- Papers and Notes, 1977-1982 (Box 3, Folder 33)
  Solid-Fluid Interface
- Papers on Long Range Order, 1966-1979 (Box 3, Folder 34)
- Papers, 1969-1997 (Box 3, Folder 35)
  Sticky Note: The reanalysis of select data
- Papers, 1977-1997 (Box 3, Folder 36)
- Papers on Voronoi Polyhedra, 1979-1989 (Box 3, Folder 37)
- Papers and Notes, 1996-1997 (Box 3, Folder 38)
  Francesco/ Vacancies
- Papers, 1979-1992 (Box 3, Folder 39)
  Vacancies- Classical Refs.
- Papers, 1996 (Box 3, Folder 40)
- Papers and Correspondence- Francesco, 1993-1999 (Box 3, Folder 41)
- Papers and Graphs, 1997 (Box 3, Folder 42)
  Basu- Vacancies
- Papers and Abstracts, 1999 (Box 3, Folder 43)
  Modes in Solid Helium (Basu)
- Graphs, Undated (Box 3, Folder 44)